Finding Aid for Kelsey Museum of Archaeology papers 1890-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Carthage Excavations, 1975; 1979
  - Excavation records
    - Volume 3-Chapter 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Volume 3-Chapter 3 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Volume 3-Chapter 4 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Volume 3-Chapter 5 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Volume 3-Chapter 5 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Volume 3-Chapter 6 (Editor's Copy) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Volume 3-Camera ready and proofs (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Volume 3-Plates and figures (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Volume 3-Duplicate Photos (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Volume 4-Preliminaries and Chapter 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Volume 4-Chapter 2 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Volume 4-Chapter 3 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Volume 4-Chapter 4 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Volume 4-Chapter 5 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Volume 4-Chapter 6 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Volume 4-Extra Prints (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Volume 4-Camera ready (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Notebooks M, E (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Notebooks M, E-K (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Notebooks M2 pi-E (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Notebooks M2 pi-E Cistern probe (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Notebooks M2-D-2 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - M2-Q-k (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Pottery Quantifications (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Pottery Summaries (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Pottery and coins lists-PBS coins cm, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Register of drawn and photographed pots (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Coin registry (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Coin 7-544 to 7-1225 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Coin 7-1226 to 7-1836 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Coin 7-1837 to 7-2382 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Volume 5, Chapter 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Volume 5, Chapter 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Volume 5, Appendix 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Volume 5, Chapter 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Volume 5, Appendix 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Volume 5, Chapter 3 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - AJA 1978-Carthage Newsletter (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Lecture (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Volume 6-Preface-Etc (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Volume 6-Chapter 1 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Volume 6-Chapter 1-Appendices (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Volume 6-Chapter 2 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Volume 6, Chapter 3 (Coins) (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Volume 6, Chapter 4 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Volume 6, Chapter 5 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Volume 6, Chapter 5 (Appendices) (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Volume 6, Chapter 6 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Volume 6, Chapter 7 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Manuscript in print (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Coin Registry 7-1 to 7-347 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Coin Registry 7-348 to 7-581 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Coin Registry 7-582 to 7-888 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Coin Registry 7-889 to 7-1183 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Coin Registry 7-1184 to 7-1615 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Coin Registry 7-1616 to 7-2137 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Coin Registry 7-2138 to 7-2519 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Coin Registry 7-2520 to 7-2856 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Coin Hoard M3J CM-78 H1, to CH-4-2 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Two bags of check note cards
    - Volume 7, Chapter 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Volume 7, Chapter 2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Volume 7, Chapter 3 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Volume 7, Chapter 3 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Two bags of check note cards
    - Volume 7, Chapter 4 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Volume 7, Chapter 5 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Volume 7, Chapter 5, first draft (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Volume 7, Chapter 6 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Volume 7, Chapter 7 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Lecture JHH (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Summary sheets supplies (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Summary sheets labor (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Summary sheets land and structures (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Internal travel (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Field supplies (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Mail rent communications (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - International transportation (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Food etc. (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Food Receipts, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Food Receipts, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Living Expenses, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Authorization letters (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Published Bks-Volumes 1-4 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Maps-Stratigraphy and sites (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous Publication Plates (Box 6A)
    - Miscellaneous Mounted Publication Plates (Box 6B)
    - Oversized Rolled Publication Plates (Tube 6C)
      (housed in oversize folder, UBimul C450)
Indexes
Indexes to Francis W. Kelsey Papers
Francis W. Kelsey papers, Appendix A: Subject Index
American Academy in Rome Boring, William A. (4.2-4.3) Butler, Nita L. (4.18) Carter, Jesse B. (7.7-7.9) Mead, William Rutherford (23.3) Moses, Lionel (24.6) Rand, E. K. (27.3-27.4) Stevens, Graham P. (31.9-31.11) Trowbridge, Breck (33.6) Van Buren, Albert W. (33.12) West, Andrew F. (35.5-35.7 and 56.4-56.6) American Philosophical Association Bill, Clarence (3.7) American School in China Freer, Charles (48.12 and 67.6) Walcott, Charles (48.16) Warner, Langdon (48.13 and 48.17) American School in Jerusalem Clay, Albert (7.17) Coffin, William (9.1) American School in New Mexico Hewett, Edgar L. (16.1-16.4) Kelsey, Ruth (20.1-20.2) Archeological Institute of America Carroll, Mitchell (6.1-6.13 and 7.1-7.6) Clay, Robert (7.17) Egbert, James C. (11.5-11.16) Frothingham, A. L. (40.6) Gotheil, Richard (14.3-14.5) Magoffin, Ralph V. D. (22.3-22.6) Seymour, Thomas D. (41.1-41.3) Shipley, F. W. (30.7-30.10) White, John Williams (40.9-40.10) Wilson, Harry L. (36.4) Armenian Manuscripts, see Manuscripts, Armenian Armenian Massacre Bristol, Mark L. (4.7) Cratherns, C. F. H. (9.10) Fuller, Harold De Wulf (13.8) Merrill, John E. (23.6) Witter, W. F. (38.7) Art and Archaeology Robinson, David M. (28.1) Carroll, Mitchell Asiatic Institute Mc Cormick, Frederick (23.2) Askren Glass and Pottery Askren, David (82.4) Harden, D. B. (15.12) Assyrian Tablets, see Tablets, Assyrian August Mau Amelung, Walter (1.6 and 44.6) Delbrueck, R. (44.7) Dodge, Cleveland (44.6) Mau, August (44.2) Warren, Langford H. (44.8) Beautus Manuscript see Manuscripts, Beautus Belgian Relief Committee Baker, George Barr (2.7 and 86.3) Ottoway, E. J. (86.6) Sink, Charles A. (86.10) Sleeper, A. E. (86.11) Bement Coins, see Coins, Bement Benefactors Anderson, John W. (1.7) Backus, Standish (2.5) Boyer, Joseph (4.4-4.5) Ferry, Dexter M. (12.13) Freer, Charles (13.11, 67.1-67.8 and 68.1-68.9) Gray, David (14.7) Gray, Philip (14.11) Inglis, James (18.5) Longyear, Mary Beecher (21.12) Murphy, William H. (24.7-24.8) Pendleton, Catherine B. (25.14-25.15) Russel, John R (28.8-28.9) Stearnsm Frederick K. (31.6) Warburg, Paul (34.12) Webber, Oscar (35.1) Webber, Richard (35.2) British Museum Bell, H. Idris (82.10-82.12) Budge, E. Wallace (83.7) Cooke, C. P. (9.6) Crumm, W. E. (9.13) Edwards, E. (83.7) Gilson, J. P. (13.13) Hall, H. R. (18.1) Hill, George F. (84.5) Read, Hercules (27.5) Carnegie Foundation Finch, George A. (12.14) Scott, James Brown (30.4-30.5) Casts, Slides Ashby, Thomas (2.4) China Freer, Charles (48.12 and 67.8) Warner, Langdon (34.13) Classical Association of the Middle West and South Barber, Grove (44.3) Barton, H. J. (2.11) Lord, Louis E. (21.16) Miller, Walter (23.9) Smiley, Charles N. (32.6) Classical Journal Miller, Frank J. (24.11 and 90.9) Coins Bement Bement, Clarence (5.2) Moore, Bertha Bement (24.11) Dattari Askren, David (82.2) Bement, Clarence (5.2) Cooke, C. P. (9.6) Freer, Charles (67.3-67.4 and 67.7) Greene, Belle Da Costa (14.4) Harden, D. B. (15.12) Hutchins, Harvey B. (64.9) Sanders, Henry A. (29.3) Smith, Shirley W. (66.3-66.5) Eastman Hutchins, Harvey B. (65.5) Electrotypes Cooke, C. P. (9.6) Harsha Hutchins, Harvey B. (65.3) Smith, Shirley W. (66.6) Karanis Bell, H. Idris (82.12) Wines Hutchins, Harvey B. (65.3) Miscellaneous Askren, David (82.2-82.3) Bishop, William W. (63.6) Breccia, E. (5.4) Gilson, J. P. (13.13) Greene, Belle Da Costa (14.14) Harden, D. B. (15.12) Hutchins, Harvey B. (65.4) Seltman, C. L. (112.1) Wood, Howland (38.8) Colleagues Abroad Ashby, Thomas (2.4) Bezard, J. (3.6) Cagnat, Rene (5.7) Diamantopolis (11.11) Dittman, G. (11.1) Gardner, Percy (13.12) Grenfell, Bernard (15.13) Harris, Rendel (15.13) Jones, H. Stuart (18.12) Reid, James S. (27.6) United States Anderson, E. H. (2.4) Breasted, James H. (4.6) Butler, Nicholas Murray (4.7) Clark, Charles Upson (7.15) Cook, Walter W. S. (9.5) Fairbanks, Arthur (12.5-12.7) Gottheil, Richard (14.3-14.5) Hyvernat, Henry (17.11-17.15) Lodge, J. E. (21.8) Lythgoe, Albert M. (21.19) Mc Cormick, Frederick (23.2) Merriam, John C. (23.5) Miller, Walter (23.10) Rhees, Rush (27.7) Richter, Gisela (27.9) Smiley, Charles (32.6) Springer, Frank (31.4) Wace, A. J. B. (34.5) Walcott, Charles S. (34.6-34.7, 48.16) Warner, Langdon (34.13) West, Andrew (35.5-35.7) Westermann, W. L. (35.8-35.10) Wilson, Harry L. (36.4) Wissler, Clark (38.7) Wood, Howland (38.8) Woodward, Robert (36.10) Worrel, W. H. (37.1-37.9) Coptic Manuscripts, see Manuscripts, Coptic Coptic Type Freer, Charles (67.5) Hecker, Frank J. (15.14) Cuneform Tablets, see Tablets, Cuneform Cyrene, see Expeditions, Cyrene Dattari Coins, see Coins, Dattari Dignitaries Miscellaneous Bryce, James (4.13) Belin, F. L. (5.2) Berenson, Bernard (5.2) Capps, Edward (5.6) Carr, Wilbur (5.12) Dana, John Cotton (11.10) Hughes, Charles Evans (17.9) Mc Cormick, Cyrus H. M. (23.1) Morgan, J. Pierpont (24.5) Morgenthau, Henry (24.11) Sleeper, A. E. (86.1) Van Horne, William (34.1) Wilson, Woodrow (36.5) Worcester, Dean C. (36.11-36.12) U.S. Congressmen Beakes, Samuel W. (3.1) Michener, Earl C. (24.11) U.S. Senators Borah, William E. (5.4) Couzens, James (9.8) Newberry, Truman H. (25.1) Eastman Coins, see Coins, Eastman Editors Graves, R. H. (14.6) More, Paul E. (24.1) Paton, James M. (28.1) Robinson, David M. (28.1) Sedgewick, Ellery (30.6) Williams, Charles R. (36.2) Emergency Society for German and Austrian Art and Science Boaz, Franz (3.12) Electrotype Coins, see Coins, Electrotype Expeditions Cyrene Armour, Allison (1.11, 70.7) Brooks, Noah W. (70.8) Fairbanks, Arthur (12.5-12.7, 70.9) Hoppin, Joseph C. (70.12) Lane, Gardner (70.6, 70.13-70.15) Norton, Richard (25.4-25.5, 70.1-70.6) Palestine Rowe, Alan (28.6) 1920-1921 Allen, Henry (1.4) Backus, Standish (2.5) Bishop, William W. (83.1) Boyer, Joseph (4.4-4.5) Bristol, Mark (4.7) Ferry, Dexter M. Jr. (12.13) Freer, Charles (68.9) Gerassimos, Father (71.8) Gray, David (14.7) Gray, Phillip (14.11) Greene, Belle Da Coasta (14.15) Hutchins, Harvey B. (65.5) Stevens, Henry G. (32.7) 1924-1925 Askren, David (82.6) Buckler, William H. (4.14) French, George (79.6) Gsell, S. (79.7) Harden, D. B. (15.12, 79.8) Jones, H. Stuart (18.12) Maloney, William J. M. A. (22.7) Merriam, John C. (23.5, 79.9-79.10) Ponssot, Louis (79.1-79.2, 80.1) Stanley, Albert A. (62.9) Stoever, Edward R. (80.2) Swain, George (73.3, 111.1-111.4) Wace, A. J. B. (34.5) White, H. G. Evelyn (80.3) Freer Estate 1919-1921 (13.3) Hecker, Frank J. (15.14) Rhodes, Katherine N. (27.9) Freer Gallery 1922-1923 (13.4) Freer, Charles (67.6) Freer Manuscripts, see Manuscripts, Freer Freer Miniatures Morey, Charles (24.2-24.4) Frieze Diary Bishop, William W. (83.1) Butler, Orma (85.5) Hutchins, Harvey B. (65.4-65.5) Kelsey, Ruth (20.2) Walker, Bryant (34.9) German Archeological Institute Adams, Edward (2.4) Amelung, Walter (1.6) Gold Monograph, see Humanistic Series Gold Objects Angell, James B. (64.3) Breasted, James H. (4.6) Dennison, Walter (10.8-10.11) Freer, Charles (67.4, 67.6-67.7) Harsha Coins, see Coins, Harsha E. C. Hegler Fund Carus, Paul (7.10) Hill Auditorium Carus, Paul (7.10) Coppicus, F. C. (9.7) Hutchins, Harvey B. (64.9) Kahn, Albert (19.1) Humanistic Series Anderson, John W. (1.7) Backus, Standish (2.5) Burton, Marion L. (64.4-64.8) Clements, W. R. (53.2) Freer, Charles (67.1-68.10) Hutchins, Harvey B. (65.4) Research and Publications Memo (69.7) Smith, Shirley (66.7) Inscriptions Box 84a Thomas Spencer Jerome Andrews, Alice Tweed (1.9) Andrews, Edith (1.10) Buckley, Paul (66.2) Burton, Marion L. (64.6) Byington, Homer (5.6) Carr, Wilbur J. (5.12) Carter, Jesse B. (7.9) Cerio, Ignazio (10.2) Freer, Charles (67.7, 68.1, 68.5-68.7) Gardner, Percy (13.12) Hecker, Frank J. (15.14) Hoyt, Hobart (17.5-17.8) Hutchins, Harvey B. (65.1) Koch, Theodore (63.13) Magoffin, Ralph V. D. (22.5) Moore, Charles (23.1, 23.12-23.14) Pendleton, Catherine B. (25.14) Pine, John B. (26.1) Putman, George H. (26.5-26.7) Rand, E. K. (27.3-27.4) Robbins, Nathaniel (28.12) Smith, Shirley W. (66.8) Stevens, Graham P. (31.9-31.11) Van Buren, Albert W. (33.12) West, Andrew (35.5) Westermann, W. L. (35.8-35.10) Winter, John G. (36.9) Karanis Coins, see Coins, Karanis Karanis Tapestries Valentioner, W. R. (33.11) Kelsey, Francis Willey Personal Data Askren, Alice (1.12) Askren, Charles (1.13) Askren, David (1.14) Askren, Leslie (2.1-2.2) Buckley, Paul (66.2) Colby, Fred (9.2) Cowie, David M. (10.3) Fay, Harriet K. (12.11) Howard, Horace H. (18.3) Howes, William E. (17.4) Kelsey, Charlotte (19.5, 54.5-54.6) Kelsey, Frederick T. (19.7) Kelsey, Frederick W. (19.8) Kelsey, Horatio Nelson (19.9) Kelsey, Ruth (20.1-20.2) Little, Clarence (65.7) Stearns, Alfred E. (31.5) Underwood, William (33.10) Wilgus, H. L. (36.1) Williams, Charles R. (36.2) Wiltsie, Charles (36.6-36.8) Lausane Treaty Borah, Williams E. (5.4) Hughes, Charles Evans (17.9) Manuscripts Armenian Anderson, E. H. (2.4) Beach, Joseph (5.2) Bishop, William W. (83.5) Gardner, Percy (13.12) Monroe, Paul (24.11) Tonapetean, P. (33.4) White, Lee A. (35.15) Beautus Cook, Walter W. S. (9.5) Dealers Beatty, Chester (3.3) Coptic Askren, David (1.14) Crumm, W. E. (9.13) Diamantopoulis (11.11) Freer, Charles (67.3) Gottheil, Richard (14.3-14.5) Grote-Hahn, Frau K. (15.4) Hutchins, Harvey B. (64.9) Hyvernat, Henry (17.11-17.15) Freer Askren, David (82.2) Breasted, James H. (4.6) J. Cushing Company (69.12) Dennison, Walter (10.8-10.11, 69.3) Freer, Charles (69.1-69.12) Gottheil, Richard (14.3-14.5) Hyvernat, Henry (17.11-17.15) Kenyon, Frederick (69.4) Lodge, J. E. (21.8) Ramsay, William C. (27.1-27.2, 69.6) Sanders, Henry A. (69.2) Smith, Shirley W. (66.3-66.4) Worrell, W. H. (37.1-37.9) Grotious Breasted, James H. (4.6) De Groot. Memos (94.11) Finch, George A. (12.14, 94.5) Johnson, J. de M. (18.13) Scott, James Brown (30.4-30.5, 94.7) Wright, Herbert F. (94.8) Morgan Breasted, James H. (4.6) Dennison, Walter (10.18-10.11) Freer, Charles (67.5) Gottheil, Richard (14.3-14.5) Greene, Belle da Costa (14.12-14.16) Gregory, Casper R. (15.2) Hyvernat, Henry (17.11-17.15) Morgan, J. Pierpont (24.5) Thurston, Ada (33.2) Norton Fairbanks, Arthur (12.5-12.7) Norton, Richard (25.4-25.5) Virgil Dennison, Walter (136.5) Miscellaneous Diamantopolis (11.11) Goldstein, Fred (13.15) Hall, H. R. (18.1) Horton, George (17.1) Hoskier, H. C. (17.2) Lodge, J. E. (21.8) Lowe, E. A. (21.17) Peet, William W. (25.13) Robbins, Frank E. (27.10) Military History Spaulding, Oliver L. (31.1-31.3) Multi-Areas Freer, Charles (13.3-13.4, 13.11, 67.1-67.8, 68.1-68.10, 69.1-69.16) Greene, Belle da Costa (14.2-14.16) Hyvernat, Henry (17.11-17.15) Moore, Charles (23.12-23.14) Sanders, Henry A. (29.3-29.9, 69.2, 136.5) Swain, George (32.1-32.3) Music Kelsey, Ruth (20.1-20.2) Lockwood, Albert (21.7) Sink, Charles (61.5-65.9, 62.1-62.4) Stanley, Albert A. (62.5-62.9) Papyri Anderson, John W. (1.7, 82.1) Askren, David (1.14, 82.2-82.9) Austin, Willard (2.3) Bacon, Paul (2.6) Baird, Charles (5.1) Bell, H. Idris (82.10-82.12) Bill, Clarence (3.7, 83.7) Bishop, William W. (83.11-83.6) Boak, Arthur E. R. (3.11) Bonner, Campbell (3.14) Breasted, James H. (4.6) Brummer, Joseph (83.7) Budge, E. Wallace (83.7) Burton, Marion L. (64.4-64.8, 83.7) Capps, Edward (5.10) Crumm, W. E. (9.13) Cumont, Franz (10.4) Diamantopoulis (11.11) Djoannu, John E. (83.7) Edgar, C. C. (83.7) Edwards, E. (83.7) Eitrem, S. (83.7) Garrett, Robert (84.5) Gejou, I. Elias (83.8-83.9) Goudi, Mr. (84.5) Greene, Belle da Costa (14.16, 84.5) Grenfell, Bernard (15.3-15.4) Harris, Rendel (15.13) Hecker, Frank J. (15.14) Hill, George F. (84.5) Hunt, A. S. (64.1) Hutchins, Harvey B. (65.5) Hyvernat, Henry (17.14) Johnson, A. C. (64.5) Kalebdjian, Freres (84.5) Kenyon, Frederick (84.2) Kondilios, A. N. (20.10) Kraemer, Casper J. (84.5) Lacau, P. (84.11) Laird, A. G. (22.1) Lake, Kirsopp (84.6) Lamacraft, Charles (84.11) Lloyd, Alfred H. (56.2-56.6) Lodge, J. E. (84.11) Longyear, Mary Beecher (21.12-21.14) Lybyer, Albert H. (84.14) Nahman, Maurice (
Francis W. Kelsey papers, Appendix B: Photographs
Fayoum area (12.18) Coptic box (17.14) Ruth Kelsey (20.2) Pendleton Scholarship winners (25.14-25.15) Coptic men (37.6) August Mau Memorial (44.1) Lung men of China (48.12) Charles Walcott (48.16) China photographs (48.17) American Academy in Rome (51.3) Catalogue of Deane pottery collection (54.5) Members of the cast of Iphigenia (54.7) A fragment found at Patmos (71.10) Patmos Expedition (72.4-72.6) D. B. Harden photos of sites and objects, 1920 expedition (79.4) Pottery in various museums (79.8) H. S. Washington (80.4) Carthage (80.5) Askren glass collection (82.4) 1925-1927 Expedition (82.12) Etruscan Ash Urn (84a.4) Belgian Relief Commission (87.13) Richard Norton, and illustrations for his book (92.11) 1920 Expedition (96.8) Aerial photos of Caesar's battlefields (97.4) Pompeii wall illustrations (120.3) Pompeii, Lo Sacco (121.5) Pompeii, miscellaneous photos (125) Pompeii, miscellaneous photos (126.1-126.4) Pompeii, miscellaneous photos (128) Pompeii, miscellaneous photos (129.1-129.2) Rome (130) Rome, churches (131.1-131.2) Rome (131.4) Rome (133.1-133.2) Sites and Monuments (135-136) William Bishop (142.3) Alice Donnelly (145.5) Fred S. Dunham (145.6) Emery B Lease (148.7) Raleigh Nelson, students in costume (150.6)
Related Material
The Kelsey Museum of Archaeology retained some archival material - notably material documenting its artifact collection. The Bentley Historical Library has a separate collection of Francis Willey Kelsey papers which complement the material in the Kelsey Museum papers.